Kelly Money, M.A.

kellylmoney@protonmail.com | 425-623-4829

I'm a former teacher turned data analyst with extensive experience working with Excel, R, SQL, Domo, and Tableau. Data wrangling is totally my jam. I enjoy creating tools for reproducible data cleaning and visualization. I love using data to answer questions and solve problems!

Professional Status

PERFORMANCE MARKETING ANALYST | FILEVINE, INC | JULY 2022 - CURRENT

- Use R to create weekly audits of all data coming in through lead generation channels
- Audit performance marketing data, surface any discrepancies or problems, and create a robust reporting engine
- Collaborate with other team members to refine metric and attribute definitions for company-wide adherence
- Work with members of the Performance Marketing team to create both high level and granular reports from the marketing
 and sales data in order to improve and refine business focus and activities.
- Create and present predictive analyses reports in R

Education

B.S INFORMATION SYSTEMS – BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY - DATABASE ADMINISTRATION AND DATA WAREHOUSING | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY - DATA ANALYTICS | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY - INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

M.A. COMPOSITION RHETORIC/ENGLISH | MISSOURI STATE UNIVERSITY

B.A. ENGLISH | MISSOURI STATE UNIVERSITY

Prior Experience

DATA OPERATIONS CONSULTANT | FILEVINE, INC | OCTOBER 2020 - JULY 2022

- Cleaning, transforming, and mapping and migrating data using R and Excel
- Assist in planning and managing the data migration process
- Responsible for meeting with stakeholders in order to discuss and understand their current data software and what their data requirements will be going forward
- Responsible for auditing existing data and addressing errors while also triaging any issues that arose during implementation
- Responsible for cleaning, mapping, and aligning data to effectively move data between software
- Make recommendations to address implementation needs as well as assess technical feasibility

DATA ANALYST | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY | JANUARY 2019 – OCTOBER 2020

- Data reporting using business intelligence tools (i.e., Tableau workbooks and dashboard design)
- Data collecting, analyzing, tracking methods and techniques
- Verifying, cleaning, and understanding of research data (SQL)
- Thorough understanding of privacy and compliance issues regarding personal data

Skills & Abilities

Programming Languages: SQL, Bash, R

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Tableau, Domo, RapidMiner

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux Databases: MSSQL Server, Oracle, MySQL

Other: Technical writing for employee documentation